# William Tremblay

# (Senior Web & Mobile Developer)

Pohjoisesplanadi 11,Helsinki, Finland | +358 93101642 | champion5star247963@gmail.com

### Summary

Full-stack engineer with over 7 years of experience in web development, managing all aspects of the development process.

Worked on 20+ projects and solved complex business problems in various industries including marketing, healthcare, and eCommerce.

Consistently saved costs while increasing profits.

# Skills React Angular Vue

## **Work Experience**

Senior Software Developer

2019.4 - 2020.3

### **ASPIRITY**

- Served as a second developer on a system modernization project.
   Built the app architecture and design system components.
- Implemented workflows and guidelines for code consistency, readability, maintainability, and testability.
- Conducted R&D (research and development) for libraries and ways to improve our codebase.
   Helped and mentored junior developers from various backgrounds.

### Senior Software Developer

2015-07 - 2018-04

### NATURAILY

- Maintained and improved the client portal React application.
- Implemented workflows and guidelines for code consistency, readability, maintainability, and testability.
- Conducted R&D (research and development) for libraries and ways to improve our codebase.
- Refactored and upgraded the continuous integration code of our main repository and created a gem to make available to other projects.
   Initiated the migration of our CI infrastructure from AWS to Google Kubernetes Engine.

### Senior Web Developer

2013.01 - 2015-04

### **EVINCE DEVELOPMENT**

Modeled the future database for iOS CycleMap application. Wrote scripts that automated the decisions to add bike lanes to the application.

Created multiple web tools to use and modify the data in the database. Developed a test automation and report generation application for an information system used in local community service centers.

# Node.js

HP

Laravel

Python

Django

MongoDB

MySQL

Bootstrap/CSS/Html

Javascript

### Education

Bachelor of Computer Science

2008 - 2012

Helsinki University